<u>andy@atwigg.com</u> CA 94002 6502454007

I'm a computer scientist with expertise in large-scale data processing and ML.

I currently lead ML efforts at Lacework, a cloud security company treating security as a big data problem. I have been an entrepreneur (CTO of 2 acquired startups Acunu, C9) and an academic (PhD Cambridge, and I was a Fellow in Computer Science at Oxford University 2008-13).

Experience

2020-present: Distinguished engineer, Lacework

Lacework is a cloud security company treating security detection as a big data problem. I lead the core "polygraph" technology – large-scale data processing and ML pipelines. We process several billion msgs/hr from agent and cloud logs. Team of ~20 engineers, 3 TL and 2 EM. Lacework raised ~\$1.8B at a ~\$8.3B valuation, and was acquired by Fortinet in 2024.

- rewrote implementation from golang to pyspark, EC2 savings of ~\$2m/yr, ~10x reduction in SEVs
- led new models using inductive GNNs with pytorch-geometric, streaming density estimators

2018-2020: EIR (entrepreneur in residence), Milliways Ventures

Exploring ideas around deep RL. One project was to try to train a model to learn how to trade using RL. I collected several TBs of L3 data from a large crypto exchange and built an event-driven simulator that allows better queue length estimation (eg due to cancellations). I supervised Stanford CS246 students who worked on it as coursework. code: https://github.com/andytwigg/deeptrade

2014-2017: CTO, C9 and Chief Scientist, Insidesales.com

C9 built one of the first systems to <u>apply ML to improve sales efficiency</u> via bottom-up forecasting, etc. C9 was <u>acquired by insidesales.com</u> in 2015. I led the data science and machine learning teams.

2013: Founder, Featurestream.io

I built a <u>streaming random forest</u> on spark streaming and experimented with offering it via an API. Code: https://github.com/featurestream/

2009-13: Cofounder, CTO, Acunu (acquired)

We built a streaming analytics system based on Cassandra, sketching algorithms, and <u>Stratified B-trees</u>, which are a fully-versioned LSM/fractal tree (see <u>here</u>, <u>here</u>). We started the London Big Data meetup. Acquired by a big tech company.

2008-13: Fellow in Computer Science, St Johns College, University of Oxford Academic post (elected by open competition); took a sabattical to found Acunu.

2006-7: Microsoft Research (Cambridge) and Technicolor Research (Paris)

Developed algorithms for P2P streaming problems with optimal throughput/latency tradeoffs.

Education

2006: PhD Computer Science, Cambridge University (King's College)

Thesis: Approximate graph routing with failures. Nominated for BCS Best Dissertation Award.

1999-2002: BSc Computer Science, Warwick University (top 1st)

Teaching

I have taught various courses at Oxford & Cambridge including Randomized Algorithms, Data Structures and Algorithms, Probability, Complexity Theory.

I enjoy DIY, drumming, golf. I rowed for Cambridge Lightweights and King's College men's 1st VIII

Selected Publications

Persistent Cache-oblivious Streaming Indexes, arxiv, abs/1707.08186, 2017

Locality-preserving allocations problems and coloured bin packing with E Xavier., J. Theoretical CS, 2015

Stratified B-trees and versioned dictionaries. Twigg et al, HotStorage 2011

Constrained-path labellings on graphs of bounded clique-width, with B Courcelle, Theory Comput. Syst., 2010

Epidemic live streaming: optimal performance trade-offs, Bonald et al, SIGMETRICS, 2008.

Worst-case time decremental connectivity and k-edge witness problems. ArXiv,abs/0810.5477, 2008

Connectivity checking in 3-connected planar graphs with obstacles. Courcelle et al., Notes in Disc Math, 2008

Rate-optimal schemes for peer-to-peer live streaming Massoulie, Twigg,. J. Perf Eval, 65(11-12):804-822, 2008

Randomized decentralized broadcasting algorithms with Massoulie et al, INFOCOM, pages 1073-1081, 2007

Forbidden-set labelling on graphs. With Courcelle et al. PODC (LOCALITY), 2007

Compact forbidden-set routing. Bruno Courcelle and Andrew Twigg. STACS 2007.

The complexity of fixed point models of trust in distributed networks. with K Krukow, J Theoretical CS, 2007

Compact forbidden-set routing (PhD Thesis). Technical report UCAM-CL-TR-678, 2006

<u>Provably optimal decentralized broadcasting algorithms.</u> With Massoulie et al, MSR-TR- 2006-105